Contact

9769030229 (Mobile) vishal.kk@somaiya.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/vishal-kothari-29b105174 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Amazon Web Services (AWS)
Python (Programming Language)
Node.js

Certifications

CutShort Certified React Native - Advanced

CutShort Certified Python - Advanced

CutShort Certified React.js - Basic

VISHAL KOTHARI

Full Stack Developer

Mumbai

Summary

I understand how to deal with client requirements and to deliver high quality products on a timely schedule. I also have experience in all phases of product development from planning and requirement gathering, to implementing and testing. I follow aws-services and read about the different major architecture implemented. Also working on embedded systems and posix system

Experience

Proximity Works
Full-stack Developer
February 2022 - Present (1 month)
Bangalore

ARCON

Associate Software Engineer
July 2020 - February 2022 (1 year 8 months)
Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

- **Tech Stack: Node, React, Vanilla JavaScript, HTML, CSS, C, Python**
- Architected, planned and improved the entire PAM solutioning from the security aspect with server side provisioning instead of client side
- → Also Reduced the risk of PAM role rules definition on client side
- Developed a browser plugin to do login and recording of a user service on browser
- Bug Fixes and Code migration of the ARCON desktop App on Linux distro from ubuntu 18 to ubuntu 20 under mentorship of senior developer

Tata Institute of Fundamental Research (TIFR) Software Engineer (Project Member) July 2019 - July 2020 (1 year 1 month) Mumbai Area, India

- Understood basic wave functions and its implementation using programming languages
- Development of Digital pulse emulator data creation, write software for simulation and unit testing

KJSCE

Student

August 2015 - July 2020 (5 years)

TMRT

Software Engineer Intern August 2018 - March 2019 (8 months)

- Successfully implemented Object detection underwater
- Tested the UAV on simulation software
- Maneuvered the UAV underwater in pools and carried out the complete testing
- Published a research paper on the developmental process followed

Research Innovation Incubation Design Laboratory Foundation (Riidl)

Software Engineer (Inter)

August 2018 - December 2018 (5 months)

Mumbai Area, India

- Our team Got selected for Rome Maker-fare during our development
- Did socket programming, swarm simulation software and pattern algorithms for swarm drone

Education

K J Somaiya College of Engineering Vidyanagar Campus Vidyavihar Mumbai-400 077

BTech - Bachelor of Technology, Computer Engineering · (2015 - 2020)